# Jared Brogan

**Q** 1606 S 105th CT, Edwardsville, Kansas, 66111
 **M** jaredbrogan@gmail.com
 **C** (620) 687-4240

# E Professional Summary

I am an IT professional looking for new opportunities in my industry. I've worked in Health IT for the last 4 years, exceeding expectations every step of the way. I enjoy finding solutions to complex problems and creating ways to facilitate growth in automation and keeping systems available 24/7.

### **Education**

Aug 2013 – May 2017 Pittsburg, Kansas

## Bachelor of Business Administration, Pittsburg State University

• Major: Computer Information Systems

• Emphasis: System Design, Computer Security and Information Assurance

• Cumulative GPA: 3.91

# Professional Experience

Jun 2019 – Present Kansas City, Missouri

#### **Production Owner,** Cerner Corporation

- Managing several cloud services/products.
- Leveraging and improving upon automation.
- Maintaining system and service availability 24/7.
- Leading several project meetings.
- Delegating work to System Engineers.
- Creating and improving documentation.
- Promoting knowledge growth among team.
- Remediating vulnerabilities.
- Performing incident management and avoidance.
- Deploying new code to Production environments.
- Improving SLA, SLO, and SLI metrics.

Oct 2018 – Jun 2019 Kansas City, Missouri

#### Senior System Engineer, Cerner Corporation

- Facilitated the management of several cloud services/products.
- Maintained system and service availability 24/7.
- Remediated vulnerabilities.
- Performed OS patching across Linux and Windows servers.
- Performed code deployments.
- Introduced heavy use of automation, which greatly reduced manual work effort.
- Led meetings to promote standard operating procedures among the other System Engineers, thus creating an environment built on collaboration and learning.
- Improved documentation.

Jul 2017 – Oct 2018 Kansas City, Missouri

#### **System Engineer,** Cerner Corporation

- Facilitated the management of several cloud services/products.
- Maintained system and service availability 24/7.
- Remediated vulnerabilities.
- Performed server OS patching across Linux and Windows servers.
- Performed code deployments.
- Reduced TCO.



#### **Server Administration**

RHEL, Oracle Linux, CentOS, Debian, Ubuntu, Windows, Citrix

#### System | Service Monitoring

Zabbix, Splunk, New Relic, NetScout, Prometheus

#### Scripting Languages

Bash, PowerShell, Python, SQL, Ruby

### **Automation Experience**

Docker, Kubernetes, Portainer, Chef, Rundeck, Jenkins, REST APIs, Terraform, Elasticsearch